Anna Liang

Intermediate Software Developer (647) 390-0329 annaliang56@gmail.com Toronto, ON An experienced full-stack developer with a background in developing web and mobile applications in agile environments. Self-directed individual who takes initiative and efficiently manages work to achieve team objectives. Adept at collaborating with stakeholders to build out new features from its inception to deployment while consistently prioritizing the end-user experience.



Skills:

- React/React Native
- TypeScript
- JavaScript
- MongoDB
- Node.js
- Express.js
- Python
- Java
- Docker
- GraphQL



Education:

University of Toronto

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

September 2017 - April 2021 | Toronto, ON



Work Experience:

Moves / Toronto (May 2022 - December 2023)

Junior Software Developer (May 2022 - May 2023) Intermediate Software Developer (May 2023 - Dec 2023)

- Integrated a third-party vendor Alpaca to build out a brokerage pipeline that facilitated thousands of dollars of stock redemptions since launch
- Consolidated and aggregated thousands of data points into both a weekly and annual earnings performance view to unlock insights for end users
- Spearheaded two major front-end application re-brandings to update the overall look and theme to new specifications

Index Exchange / Toronto (January 2020 - April 2020)

Software Engineer

- Implemented new internal application for accumulating and forwarding Jira data to Domo - enabling flexible metric calculations and visualizations
- Orchestrated efficient software design, development, and deployment with Docker, including testing features and correcting code



Technical Projects:

La Room de Discode

- Built a collaborative videotelephony editor using Express,
 React, Node.js, MongoDB, and GraphQL
- Integrated real time synchronization with a shared Python IDE and shell, as well as video, audio, and chat communication using WebRTC and WebSockets